haider raza

🗣 Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India 🛮 raza786.haider@gmail.com 🛘 +918208470364 🛅 https://www.linkedin.com/in/haider-raza-95557b91/

https://github.com/seyedhaiderraza

SUMMARY

Senior Web Developer with 8.5+ years of work experience in building web applications for telecom, internet banking and healthcare domain. Proficient in transforming business requirements to digital web solutions through active discussions with business stakeholders, designing and coding the requirements to digital features, testing, deployment, debugging and code-fixes while learning, mentoring, and performing as a team player.

SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, React, Redux, NextJS, Node, Express, MongoDB, Typescript, GraphQL, PassportJS, GIT, SSH, AWS

EXPERIENCE

Senior Consultant Optimum Infosystems

February 2022 - May 2023, Hyderabad, India

- · Senior Web Developer at Optimum Infosystems:
- · Worked with DBS Bank to develop and enhance public webpages connecting to the Teamsite UI using React components.
- · Part of a team of developers in implementing advanced functionalities and optimizing performance to deliver a seamless user experience.

Senior Software Engineer

Larsen And Toubro Infotech

March 2018 - December 2021, Pune, India

- Successfully contributed to the development and customization of ABSA Internet Banking, including features like self-registration, enhanced fund transfers, and improved transaction history.
- · Played a key role in building and enhancing the accounts-dashboard and sweep execution functionality for Citi Global Concentration Engine, optimizing cash consolidation and improving user experience.

Senior Technical Consultant

Ohum Healthcare IT Solutions

November 2017 - February 2018, Pune, India

• Developed Docit Web app for Client Healthcare, Malta EU inventory module, enabling stock access, update alerts, and consumption reports. Improved performance and reduced development time by 20%.

Associate Software Engineer

Amdocs

June 2014 - October 2017, Pune, India

- · Developed and enhanced AT&T's Order Management System, optimizing order processing and improving flexibility for customers.
- · Provided development, testing, production support and achieved performance improvement for quicker completion times.

PROJECTS

Public Web (PWEB)

DBS, Singapore · February 2022 - May 2023

- · Environment: React, Next, Javascript, NPM, GIT, Bitbucket, VSCode, testing-library, AWS Lambda
- · Working with the team to loosely couple CMS dependency(Teamsite) by developing and enhancing UI components for different pages such as product, promotions, articles insurance, etc., segments such as treasury, digibank, personal across 2 countries India, Indonesia.
- $\cdot \ \, \text{Active Involvement in business requirements discussions, converting requirements to developing code components, unit testing, continuous integration, production support.}$
- Successfully led 2 Releases (business-live) for PWEB- India and Indonesia with team.
- Description: PWEB comprises of all public facing Websites of DBS serving 12000+ pages, 2 billion+ hits per month.
- · Achieved 10% performance improvement in Page Load Times (PLT) and increased Search Engine Optimization (SEO) score by 20%.
- · Replaced CMS dependency with React components, streamlined business logic, improved the code organization and deployment process.

ABSA Internet Banking, South Africa

Larsen and Toubro Infotech, Pune · September 2020 - December 2021

- · Environment: Bootstrap4, SASS, Javascript, React, Node Express, NPM, REST APIs Role:
- · Built self-registration feature which would allow customer to use Current, Saving or Card details to register for internet banking.
- $\cdot \ Enhanced\ and\ customized\ fund\ transfer\ feature\ to\ allow\ users\ to\ perform\ domestic\ fund\ transfer\ to\ accounts\ outside\ ABSA\ bank.$
- Enhanced and customized transaction history module which would allow customers to view history, transaction details, and fetch statements for any Current/Savings account.
- · AIB enables customers to perform financial transactions using features -self-registration, balance enquiry, e-statement, bill payments.

Citi Global concentration engine

Citigroup, US · March 2018 - August 2021

· Environment: - HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript, Angular, Node Express, NPM, REST APIs, MongoDB.

Dolo

- · Built and enhanced accounts-dashboard where users can select accounts with predefined arrangements allowing customers to skip accounts.
- Enhanced sweep execution functionality to generate an effective virtual accounts network arrangement, perform series of cash flow between account pairs and consolidation to ultimate account.

Description:

- GCE provides cash concentration from partner accounts to central account to minimize idle balances and maximise effective cash consolidation during intraday or end of day period.
- · Improved existing form fields validation mechanism to identify and restrict misconfiguration of accounts for transactions.

Docit Web

Phum Healthcare IT Solutions · November 2017 - February 2018

- · Client: Malta EU
- · Environment: HTML5/CSS3, SASS, Angular

Role

- · Built inventory module to enable user access to stock availability stock update alerts and notifications and consumption reports.
- Description: Docit is an online healthcare management system which offers doctors and patients to connect and use several online features such as patient history, appointment-booking, insurance, bill payments, inventory.
- Developed Docit web application using HTML5/CSS3, SASS and the Angular framework, resulting in improved performance, enhanced scalability, and improved data integrity, resulting in a 20% reduction in development time.

Order Management System

AT&T U.S. · June 2014 - October 2017

Environment: HTML5/CSS3, Angular, Node, Microservices, PostgreSQL.

Role:

- Built and enhanced inquire order data which manages pre and post checkout information of any AT&T orders (Telephone number, rangedial, port-in, port-out) for persist on order completion.
- Enhanced the TN-porting and TN-ordering flows which would allow customers to modify already placed orders with additional TNs, port TNs and update LSR carrier with a new carrier company.
- $\cdot \ \text{Handled production support from onshore in Guadalajara, Mexico.}$

Description: OMS records and work on all the information and processes, including order entry, inventory management, fulfilment, and post-sale services.

• Improved the performance of the OMS by 20%, resulting in quicker completion times for processing orders. Established expert level knowledge on the OMS and became the "Go to" person for questions about orders and issues with the system.

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

AWS · 2021

ID: R3YMYW4BN2BQQ334

Full-Stack Web Development with React Specialization

The Hong Kong UNiversity of Science and Technology • 2021

ID: H8ZQ57FBYWTS

EDUCATION

MASTER OF SCIENCE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

LIVERPOOL JOHN MOORE'S UNIVERSITY · UK · 2022 · 68%(merit)

POST GRADUATE DIPLOMA IN SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT

INTERNATIONAL INSTITUTE OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY \cdot BANGALORE \cdot 2021 \cdot 3.75

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING IN INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

ORIENTAL INSTITUTE OF SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY \cdot BHOPAL, India \cdot 2014 \cdot 8.1